JOHN KIM

Z cloudiosx@gmail.com **→** (917) 471-0286

in linkedin.com/in/john-kim-developer ogithub.com/cloudiosx og cloudiosx.medium.com

Professional Summary

Software engineer and entrepreneur with a strong business track record. 4 years of experience working with the latest technology solutions. Expertise in iOS and full stack web development.

Technical Skills

Languages: Swift, Python, JavaScript, SQL, CSS, HTML

Frameworks: React.js, Node.js, Flask

Technologies/Tools: iOS, Xcode, UIKit, PostgreSQL, Git, Unix, AWS, Bitrise, SumoLogic, Datadog, Periscope

Work Experience

App Academy Sep 2022 – Present

Software Engineering Assistant

New York City, NY

- Working on helping job seekers with both their portfolio project implementation as well as interview preparation.
- Ensured that students' projects have enough complexity through an adequate number of CRUD features, and aided the behavioral coach in organizing the data behind their assigned job seekers in a systematic manner.
- Conducted recurring behavioral & technical mock interviews based on each students' weaknesses.
- Prepared data structures & algorithms curriculum with technical coaches covering all technical concepts in depth, and hosted daily 2 hour live sessions for 83 people via Discord.

PagerDuty May 2022 – Aug 2022

Software Engineer Intern

New York City, NY

- Implemented core features end to end for the iOS on-call app as 1 of 3 developers using Swift.
- Completed migration from MVP to MVVM architecture with 100% coverage by writing snapshot unit tests.
- Modernized main landing page by building a dashboard to display data summaries, on-call and technical services to replace hamburger menu, and presented demo to upper leadership with resounding support from the VP.
- Enabled phased launch and monitoring by implementing all associated unit test and main app metrics in Periscope.
- Designed and developed the maintenance windows feature for custom notifications independent of the Swift framework, allowing for technical services to be organized based on activity, flexible date time selection and grouped display.

App Academy Jan 2022 – Feb 2022

Teachina Assistant

New York City, NY

• Provided auxiliary lectures to students, assisted with tasks such as weekly test preparations, and helped debug projects if they encountered any errors during daily pair programming sessions.

SN Marketing Group Ltd

Oct 2019 – May 2020

Chief Operating Officer

Seoul, South Korea

- Executed the full spectrum of duties related to oversight of company operations through sound financial stewardship by developing, coordinating, implementing, and managing the operating capital budget.
- Mitigated avoidable costs by ensuring preventative maintenance of 3rd party services such as live chat support.
- Supported co-workers through regular check-ins and optimizing Agile workflow for cross-department collaboration.

Projects

Music.ly Clone <u>live</u> | <u>demo</u>

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

- Developed a Music.ly (now called TikTok) clone with AWS, React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Python, Flask and PostgreSQL that allows people to create, share and view short videos.
- Implemented core functionalities such as user followers, profiles, news feeds and video upload.
- Designed and implemented a chunk-based video upload mechanism and workflow that handled internet disconnections during uploads and compressed videos by up to 70% to be stored on to AWS S3.
- Integrated OAuth for easy and secure user registrations and logins.

DevShare <u>iOS store</u> | <u>demo</u>

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

- Developed a novel photo sharing iOS application with Swift, Xcode, UIKit and Firebase with features such as photo news feeds, photo postings and following/unfollowing users.
- Implemented RESTful APIs for CRUD operations and employed a MVVM (Model-View-ViewModel) and MVC (Model-View-Controller) hybrid architecture with Google Firebase authentication.

Education

App Academy

Jul 2021 – Jan 2022

New York City, NY

King's College London

Full-time Software Engineering Immersive Program

Sep 2016 - May 2019

Bachelor of Arts in Liberal Arts

London, England